Planned Parenthood Federation of America Records (PPFA II): SERIES II. CLASSIFIED FILES, 1921-80 (Part 2)
Sophia Smith Collection
Planned Parenthood Federation of America Records (PPFA II): SERIES II. Classified Files (part 2)
1921-80
Planned Parenthood Federation of America
MS 371 UUID:addf81f3-f1a6-4265-a56c-0a2d7fa0c267
83 linear feet
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
Materials in this series relate to the administration of PPFA. It consists of records of the board of directors, executive committee, standing and special committees, and the various divisions and departments of the Federation. The records include correspondence, memos, by-laws, procedures, standards, press releases, reports, statistics, reference materials, and minutes. This series is the core record of Federation activities and policy development. This Series forms part of the PPFA II Records.
This Series forms part of the PPFA II Records
Materials in this series relate to the administration of PPFA. It consists of records of the board of directors, executive committee, standing and special committees, and the various divisions and departments of the Federation. The records include correspondence, memos, by-laws, procedures, standards, press releases, reports, statistics, reference materials, and minutes. This series is the core record of Federation activities and policy development.
The series is roughly arranged as follows: general policies and histories; committees, bylaws, and handbooks; annual meetings; administrative staff; and then departments and related organizations. Major departments and organizations are as follows: Center for Family Planning Program Development (which was called the Alan Guttmacher Institute beginning in 1975); Community Affairs (later known as Youth and Student Affairs); Field Department, which includes material on abortion; Financial Management; Communications (at times known as Education, Information and Education, or Public Affairs Department); Fund Raising/Resources; Medical (includes material on abortion and contraception); Research (includes clinic statistics); Family Planning International Assistance (includes reports on international family planning projects); and International Planned Parenthood Federation.
NOTE: To view the series descriptions and contents lists, click on the series links below. Some files are quite large and may take several minutes to load, depending on your internet connection.
Due to it's large size, the SERIES II container list is divided into two parts: Part 1 and Part 2.
Organization of the Collection
This collection is organized into ten series:
I. Chronological Files
II. Classified Files
Part 1
Part 2
III. Publications
IV. Subject Files
V. Affiliates
Part 1
Part 2
VI. Regions
VII. Minutes
VIII. Foreign
IX. Guttmacher
[SERIES X. Restricted]
PPFA has closed records created January 1, 1985 or later, with the exception of many published materials which are open to research. All records having to do with clinic defense and security are closed. PPFA has closed a small section of files in box 206 for fifty years. Researchers may request access to restricted materials from PPFA.
The Margaret Sanger Papers Microfilm Edition: Smith College Collection Series, edited by Esther Katz, et al., University Publications of America, 1995
Periodic additions to the collection are expected.
PPFA deposited these records in 1988. Various departments have since sent miscellaneous additions.
Best, Winfield; Guttmacher, Alan Frank, 1898-; McCormick, Katherine Dexter, 1876-1967; Rose, D. Kenneth; Sanger, Margaret, 1879-1966; Wattleton, Faye; Alan Guttmacher Institute--History; American Birth Control League--History; Abortion--Law and legislation-United States--History--Sources; Abortion services--History--Sources; Birth Control Clinical Research Bureau (New York, N.Y.)--History; Birth Control Federation of America--History; International Planned Parenthood Federation--History; Planned Parenthood Federation of America--History; Planned Parenthood-World Population (U.S.)--History; Birth control clinics--United States--History--Sources; Birth control--History--20th century--Sources; Birth control--Developing countries--History--20th century--Sources; Contraceptives--Research--History; Hygiene, Sexual--History--20th century; Human reproduction--Political aspects; Population policy--History--20th century; Reproductive health--Statistics; Sex instruction--History; Women--Health and hygiene--United States--20th century; Women's health services--United States--20th century
This Series forms part of the PPFA II Records
See also the PPFA I Records.
Related material can be found in the Margaret Sanger Papers, Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College, and at the Library of Congess.
- SERIES II. CLASSIFIED FILES (part 2)
  - 1.65 FINANCIAL MANAGEMENT
    - Accounting Handbook for Affiliates, 1973 (Box 58, Folder 41)
    - Accounts Receivable, S. Fields, Esq., 1978 (Box 58, Folder 42)
    - Allowable Business Expenses, 1972 (Box 58, Folder 43)
    - Analysis of Headquarters Expenditures, 1967-68 (Box 58, Folder 44)
    - Anderson, Richard G., Staff Correspondence & Memos, 1970-71 (Box 58, Folder 45)
    - PPFA Audits
      - 1975-80 (Box 58, Folder 46-51)
      - 1967-74 (Box 58, Folder 52-59)
    - Balance Sheet
      - 1973-74 (Box 58, Folder 60)
      - 1975-79 (Box 58)
    - BANKS
      - The Bank of New York, 1978 (Box 58, Folder 61)
      - Federal Reserve Bank, 1978 (Box 58, Folder 62)
      - Banks, First National City
        - 1973-74 (Box 58, Folder 63)
        - 1975-78 (Box 58)
      - First Women's Bank, 1977 (Box 58, Folder 64)
      - Irving Trust Company Statement of Account, 1971 (Box 58, Folder 65)
      - Banks, Correspondence, Miscellaneous & Minority
        - 1969-74 (Box 58, Folder 66)
        - 1975-78 (Box 58)
    - BROWN BROTHERS HARRIMAN & COMPANY
      - Brown Brothers Harriman & Company, 1978 (Box 58, Folder 67)
    - Chart of Accounts, 1973 (Box 58, Folder 68)
    - General Correspondence (Formerly Budget & Finance)
      - 1970-74 (Box 58, Folder 69)
      - 1975-79 (Box 58)
    - Department HEW Contract HSM 110-71-56, 1971 (Box 58, Folder 70)
    - National, Budget & Finance
      - Correspondence, 1965-69 (Box 58, Folder 71-74)
      - Dr. Guttmacher's Material, 1964-66 (Box 58, Folder 75-76)
      - Correspondence, 1958-64 (Box 58, Folder 77)
      - Mimeos, Misc., General, 1955-66 (Box 58, Folder 78)
    - Computer, Data Processing
      - 1971-74 (Box 59, Folder 1)
      - 1975-78 (Box 59)
    - Cost Accounting Project from 1973 (1/11/1972-2/20/1974) (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Diaz, Andrew W.
      - Correspondence & Memos, 1976-78 (Box 59, Folder 3)
      - Chronological, 1978 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - EMERGENCY GUIDELINES
      - Operating Expenses, Emergency Guidelines, 1970 (Box 59, Folder 5)
      - Financial Statements, 1967-71 (Box 59, Folder 6)
      - Financial Report, Definitions, 1972 (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Gibson, Betram Vice President for Finance
      - Appointment, 1979 (Box 59, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence & Memos, 1979-80 (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Guide for Uniform Accounting and Financial Reporting, Planned Parenthood Federation of America, Inc., 1967 (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - Grant Financial Management
      - OEO No. 2115 SW Region Migrant Project, 1970-71 (Box 59, Folder 11)
      - Dept. HEW H-1968-1 (C2) Research, 1971 (Box 59, Folder 12)
      - Public Health Cal. Grants Management Agreement #514, 1971 (Box 59, Folder 13)
      - Dept HEW H-1681 (C1) (R), 1971 (Box 59, Folder 14)
    - Hyacinthe, L., Affiliate Accounting, Correspondence, 1976 (Box 59, Folder 15)
    - Income & Appropriations, 1964-68 (Box 59, Folder 16)
    - Robert Bowling, Invoices, Hyacinthe, 1973-74 (Box 59, Folder 17)
    - Income & Expenditures
      - 1972-74 (Box 59, Folder 18)
      - 1975-79 (Box 59)
      - 1963-68 (Box 59, Folder 19)
    - International Business Machines Corp., Correspondence, 1970-73 (Box 59, Folder 20)
    - Internal Revenue Service, 1970-73 (Box 59, Folder 21)
    - Investments
      - General, Miscellaneous
        - 1978 (Box 59, Folder 22)
        - 1972-74 (Box 59, Folder 23)
      - Golden Account, 1974 (Box 59, Folder 24)
      - McCormick Bequests, 1974 (Box 59, Folder 25)
    - Marren, James
      - Analysis of Investment Account
        - 1970-74 (Box 59, Folder 26)
        - 1976 (Box 59)
      - Correspondence & Memos
        - 1975-78 (Box 59, Folder 27)
        - 1970-74 (Box 59, Folder 28-29)
      - Indirect Rate Negotiations
        - 1971-74 (Box 59, Folder 30)
        - 1975-77 (Box 59)
    - Mimeos, Memos, General
      - 1971-74 (Box 59, Folder 31)
      - 1975-77 (Box 59)
    - New Policy on Overdue Accounts, Correspondence and Memos
      - 1974 (Box 59, Folder 32)
      - 1975 (Box 59)
    - Peat, Marwick, Mitchell & Co.
      - Subject, 1962-65 (Box 59, Folder 33)
      - Action Plan for Reviewing Internal Accounting Controls, 1978 (Box 59, Folder 34)
      - Accounting System for Project Activities, 1969 (Box 59, Folder 35)
      - Indirect Cost Accounting Project, 1971-73 (Box 59, Folder 36)
    - Revenues 1975-77 (Box 59, Folder 37)
    - REVIEWING FUND ADVANCES
      - Revolving Fund Advances, 1973 (Box 59, Folder 38)
      - Schedule 1967 Unrestricted Department Funds, 1967 (Box 59, Folder 39)
    - Scudder, Stevens, & Clark
      - 1970-74 (Box 59, Folder 40)
      - 1975-78 (Box 59)
    - Utility charges, 1974 (Box 59, Folder 41)
    - Wachter, Larry
      - Correspondence & Memos
        - 1973-74 (Box 59, Folder 42)
        - 1975-79 (Box 59)
      - PB & IA, Corporate Rates, 1977-78 (Box 59, Folder 43)
      - Chronological
        - 1973-74 (Box 59, Folder 44)
        - 1975-77 (Box 59)
    - Watkins, Bea, Correspondence and Memos, 1977-79 (Box 59, Folder 45)
  - Insurance
    - Doyle, Robert
      - Correspondence, 1980-81 (Box 59, Folder 46)
      - Memos ,General Risk Management, 1980 (Box 59, Folder 47)
    - National Insurance Program, Coverage & Costs, 1980 (Box 59, Folder 48)
    - All Risk Associates, Inc., 1975-79 (Box 59, Folder 49)
    - American International Group, 1978 (Box 59, Folder 50)
  - Financial Management
    - Comprehensive Dishonesty, Disappearance & Distribution Insurance (3D)
      - 1972-74 (Box 60a, Folder 1)
      - 1975-79 (Box 60a)
    - Bonding & Forgery
      - 1969-74 (Box 60a, Folder 2)
      - 1975-76 (Box 60a)
  - Insurance
    - (Stephan York) Bower & Gardner, 1977-79 (Box 60a, Folder 3)
    - Brooks, Shettle & Garman
      - Legal, (Paul, Eve), 1979 (Box 60a, Folder 4)
      - 1977-79 (Box 60a, Folder 5)
    - California Insurance
      - Commissioner, 1978 (Box 60a, Folder 6)
      - Guarantee Association, 1978-79 (Box 60a, Folder 7)
    - Consent for Settlement, 1978 (Box 60a, Folder 8)
    - Contractual Arrangements, Legal (Paul), 1978-79 (Box 60a, Folder 9)
    - Corbin, Jill Claims Coordinator Correspondence & Memos, 1979 (Box 60a, Folder 10)
    - Development of New Insurance Programs, 1978 (Box 60a, Folder 11)
  - Financial Management, Directors & Officers, Liability Insurance
    - 1972-74 (Box 60a, Folder 12)
    - 1975-79 (Box 60a)
  - Insurance, Directors and Officers, Liability & Corporation Reimbursement Policy, 1979 (Box 60a, Folder 13)
  - Financial Management
    - Insurance, Erisa, 1975-76 (Box 60a, Folder 14)
    - Federationwide Insurance Coverage, 1972 (Box 60a, Folder 15)
  - Gaye, Winston J. C.
    - Chronological, 1978 (Box 60a, Folder 16-17)
    - Insurance
      - Insurance Checklist for Affiliates, 1978-79 (Box 60a, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence & Memos
        - 1974 (Box 60a, Folder 19)
        - 1975-79 (Box 60a)
    - Chronological, 1978-79 (Box 60a, Folder 20-22)
  - Insurance
    - Great Southwest Insurance Company
      - 1970-74 (Box 60a, Folder 23)
      - 1975-77 (Box 60a)
    - George Betterly Consulting Group, 1978 (Box 60a, Folder 24)
  - Financial Management, National Liability Insurance, Hold Harmless, Agreements, Correspondence
    - 1970-74 (Box 60a, Folder 25)
    - 1975-78 (Box 60a)
  - Insurance
    - Insurance Advisory Committee, 1977 (Box 60a, Folder 26)
    - Insurance Meetings, 1977-78 (Box 60a, Folder 27)
    - Insurance Matters Meeting, 1973 (Box 60a, Folder 28)
    - Legal Insurance, Lloyds Policy (Paul, E.), 1978 (Box 60a, Folder 29)
  - Financial Management, Peripheral Coverage Malpractice Portion National Liability Insurance, Joint Ventures
    - 1971-74 (Box 60b, Folder 30)
    - 1975-79 (Box 60b)
  - National Comprehensive Insurance Memos, 1977-80 (Box 60b, Folder 31)
  - Financial Management, National Comprehensive Liability Insurance, Memos to Affiliates Regions
    - 1974 (Box 60b, Folder 32)
    - 1975-76 (Box 60b)
  - National Comprehensive Liability Insurance
    - Memos, 1970-73 (Box 60b, Folder 33)
    - Risk Management Memos, 1977-78 (Box 60b, Folder 34)
  - Insurance, Minutes of Insurance Meeting, 1978 (Box 60b, Folder 35)
  - Financial Management
    - MISCELLANEOUS INSURANCE
      - Insurance, Floater Policy Fred S. James & Co., 1972 (Box 60b, Folder 36)
      - 1972-74 (Box 60b, Folder 37)
      - 1975-79 (Box 60b)
  - Insurance, M & M Risk Management Service, 1978 (Box 60b, Folder 38)
  - Financial Management
    - National Liability Insurance
      - Abortion Malpractice Suits, 1973 (Box 60b, Folder 39)
      - Insurance, 1978-79 (Box 60b, Folder 40-41)
      - 1976-77 (Box 60b, Folder 42)
      - Plan for PPFA & Its Affiliates, 1977 (Box 60b, Folder 43)
      - 1976 (Box 60b, Folder 44)
      - Dr. Arnold Evaluation Abortion Facility 8/1976 from 1976 (8/4/1976-8/5/1976) (Box 60b, Folder 45)
      - 1975 (Box 60b, Folder 46)
      - Risk Management Proposal & Budget, 1975 (Box 60b, Folder 47)
      - 1972-74 (Box 60b, Folder 48-50)
      - Survey, 1970-72 (Box 60b, Folder 51)
      - Malpractice Insurance Survey & Results, 1972 (Box 60b, Folder 52)
      - 1969-71 (Box 60b, Folder 53-55)
    - Insurance
      - Office Contents Policy
        - 1973-74 (Box 60b, Folder 56)
        - 1975-79 (Box 60b)
      - Malpractice, PPIC, Directors & Officers (Paul, Eve), Legal 1978-79 (Box 60b, Folder 57)
      - PLANNED PROTECTION INSURANCE CO. LTD. (PPIC)
        - Insurance Department, Woody Beckman Consulting Actuary, Inc., 1977-80 (Box 60b, Folder 58)
        - Planned Protection Insurance Co. Ltd., Auditors Report & Financial State for the Year Ending, 1979-80 (Box 60b, Folder 59)
        - Planned Protection Insurance Co., Ltd., 1978-79 (Box 60b, Folder 60)
        - Founded PPIC Insurance Planned Protection Insurance Co., Inc., 1977 (Box 60b, Folder 61)
    - National Liability Insurance
      - Poulton & Associates
        - 1976-79 (Box 61, Folder 1)
        - 1974 (Box 61, Folder 2)
        - 1975 (Box 61)
      - Poulton & Orr, 1973-74 (Box 61, Folder 3-5)
      - Poulton & Associates
        - Reports (Box 61)
          - Hans Blaise's Files, 1976 (Box 61, Folder 6)
          - John C. Robbins' Files, 1974 (Box 61, Folder 7)
      - Retention of Medical Records, 1973 (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Reporting & Handling of Claims, National Comprehensive Public Liability Insurance
      - 1971-74 (Box 61, Folder 9)
      - 1975 (Box 61)
    - Insurance Research Project, 1978 (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - National Liability Insurance, Reserve Insurance Company, 1975-79 (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - Insurance Risk Planning Group
      - Consultants, 1978-79 (Box 61, Folder 12)
      - Insurance Progress Review & Draft Report to Affiliates, 1978 (Box 61, Folder 13)
    - S. B. Ackerman Associates, 1977 (Box 61, Folder 14)
    - National Liability Insurance
      - Signal Insurance Company
        - 1976-78 (Box 61, Folder 15)
        - 1973 (Box 61, Folder 16)
      - Use of Medical Students in Clinics (Harriet Pilpel), 1970 (Box 61, Folder 17)
    - National Insurance, Theft & Liability, R. C. Rathbone & Son, 1964-67 (Box 61, Folder 18)
    - Workman's Compensation
      - 1974 (Box 61, Folder 19)
      - 1975-78 (Box 61)
    - Pross, Albert E., Contracts Officer, 1971-73 (Box 61, Folder 20)
    - Requests to Bid, 1971 (Box 61, Folder 21)
    - Secession of Stewart Mott Transaction, 1970 (Box 61, Folder 22)
    - Fred D. Williams Insurance, Memos General, 1970-71 (Box 61, Folder 23)
  - Vice President for Communications Appointment, Bates, Don, 1979-80 (Box 61, Folder 24)
  - Affiliate Programs, 1979-80 (Box 61, Folder 25)
  - Communications
    - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 61, Folder 26)
    - Information Alerts, 1979-80 (Box 61, Folder 27)
    - Bates, Don, Memos, 1979-80 (Box 61, Folder 28)
    - Barker, Mimi
      - Backgrounder for Editorial Writers and Political Cartoons, 1980 (Box 61, Folder 29)
      - Correspondence Media Relations, 1980-81 (Box 61, Folder 30)
    - Workshop Sample for Discussion Only, 1980 (Box 61, Folder 31)
    - Mimi Barker, Media Relations, TV Memos Coordinator, 1979-80 (Box 61, Folder 32)
    - Snow, Barbara, Public Relations Manager Appointment, 1979 (Box 61, Folder 33)
    - Public Information Communications Guidelines: What We Say and How We Say It (Wattleton), 1978 (Box 61, Folder 34)
    - Report on 1979 Affiliate Public Relations/Public Affairs Questionnaire, 1979 (Box 61, Folder 35)
  - PP NEWS
    - News and Views, 1980-81 (Box 61, Folder 36)
    - Planned Parenthood News (formerly) Now PP Review, 1979-80 (Box 61, Folder 37)
  - I & E Department, Planned Parenthood News, 1977-79 (Box 61, Folder 38)
  - Publications in Focus, Fact vs. Fiction: PP vs. The Human Life Center, 1980-81 (Box 61, Folder 39)
  - Education Department
    - Correspondence, 1978-79 (Box 61, Folder 40)
    - Directory of PPFA Educators, 1980 (Box 61, Folder 41)
    - Cassell, Carol, Director of Education, Appointment, 1979 (Box 61, Folder 42)
    - Annual Meeting, Educators' Workshop, Minutes & Report, 1979 (Box 61, Folder 43)
    - Carol Cassell's Mailings, 1980 (Box 61, Folder 44)
    - Film Festival, Annual Meeting Denver, CO, 1980 (Box 61, Folder 45)
    - Cassell, Carol, Memos, 1979-81 (Box 61, Folder 46-47)
    - Results of PPFA's Education Survey December, 1979 (Box 61, Folder 48)
    - Recommendations for Establishment, 1978 (Box 61, Folder 49)
    - Needs Assessment Questionnaire for Evaluation Manual, Kirkpatricks, 1980 (Box 61, Folder 50)
  - LIBRARY
    - I & E Department, Library Budget, 1977 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - National, PP Library, Correspondence, 1966-74 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - I & E Department, Library Proposal to National Library of Medicine, 1971 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - National, Library
      - General, Memos, Mimeos, 1972-73 (Box 62, Folder 4)
      - Mimeos, Misc. & Pop. in the News, 1965-70 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Horowitz, Blanche
    - Chronological
      - 1974 (Box 62, Folder 6)
      - 1975-77 (Box 62)
      - 1973-74 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Education Department
    - Population Education
      - Act Source: Zero Population Growth, 1980 (Box 62, Folder 8)
      - Kurtz, Lynn, PhD. Director Appointment October, 1979 (Box 62, Folder 9)
      - News, 1980-81 (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - I & E Department
    - Barnes, Sherry
      - Population
        - Information, 1977-80 (Box 62, Folder 11)
        - Coordinator, Correspondence, 1977-78 (Box 62, Folder 12)
        - Information Prospect, 1977 (Box 62, Folder 13)
        - Education Workshops, 1978-79 (Box 62, Folder 14)
        - Education, 1977 (Box 62, Folder 15)
  - PPWP DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC AFFAIRS
    - Activities, Relevant Provision of the Law, Harriet Pilpel & Laurie R. Rockett, 1979 (Box 62, Folder 16)
    - Alerts, 1979 (Box 62, Folder 17)
    - Department Public Affairs Weekly Newsletter, 1981 (Box 62, Folder 18)
    - Issues Update, 1980 (Box 62, Folder 19)
    - White HouseConference on the Family, 1980 (Box 62, Folder 20)
  - Abortion Attitudes Brochure, 1980 (Box 62, Folder 21)
  - Advertising
    - Strategy Phase II, 1973 (Box 62, Folder 22)
    - Advertising Council, Inc.
      - Correspondence
        - 1970-73 (Box 62, Folder 23)
        - 1974 (Box 62, Folder 24)
        - 1975-76 (Box 62)
    - Campaign Proposal
      - 1971-74 (Box 62, Folder 25)
      - 1975-76 (Box 62)
  - Department of Public Affairs, Brochure Re: Write Gina Johnson, 1979-80 (Box 62, Folder 26)
  - Department Public Information, Sale of Consent Forms and Fact Sheets, Johnson, Gina, 1978 (Box 62, Folder 27)
  - March of Dimes, 1978 (Box 62, Folder 28)
  - National Council of Jewish Women, 1975 (Box 62, Folder 29)
  - On the Move, Annual Meeting, 1980 (Box 62, Folder 30)
  - Public Service Advertising, 1978 (Box 62, Folder 31)
  - PP in Action, Annual Meeting, 1980 (Box 62, Folder 32)
  - Department of Public Affairs, Gina Johnson, A Test of Advertising Vasectomy on Radio, 1977 (Box 62, Folder 33)
  - Vice President for Public Affairs, Dunlop, Joan, Appointment & Registration, 1979-80 (Box 62, Folder 34)
  - Public Affairs Department
    - Trichter, Jane, Correspondence, 1980 (Box 62, Folder 35)
    - Annual Meeting, Denver Hilton, Denver, CO, 1980 (Box 62, Folder 36)
    - Melanie Woolston, Correspondence, 1980-81 (Box 62, Folder 37)
    - Public Impact Plan, 1981 (Box 62, Folder 38)
  - I & E Department
    - Advertising Campaign
      - Correspondence, 1972-73 (Box 62, Folder 39)
      - Federal Communications Commission, 1972 (Box 62, Folder 40)
      - Gallup Organization
        - Trends in Public Attitudes, 1972 (Box 62, Folder 41)
        - Public Attitudes Family Size, 1971 (Box 62, Folder 42)
      - General Misc., 1973-74 (Box 62, Folder 43)
      - INAE List (Newspapers), 1972 (Box 62, Folder 44)
      - List of Newspapers by State, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 45)
      - Magazines, 1971 (Box 62, Folder 46)
    - National Advertising Campaign on "Population"
      - Report to Sponsors, 1969-72 (Box 62, Folder 47-48)
    - Advertising Council Campaign
      - Strategy Guidelines Draft, 1970 (Box 62, Folder 49)
      - Population Campaign, 1969-72 (Box 62, Folder 50)
      - Status Report, 1971-72 (Box 62, Folder 51)
    - Phew Family Planning Advertising Campaign (Box 62, Folder 52)
      - 1974 (Box 62)
      - 1975 (Box 62)
    - Public information Proposal for a Margaret Sanger Centennial Campaign, 1978, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 53)
    - Public Service Advertising Project, 1977 (Box 62, Folder 54)
      - Publicity & Promotion, 1970 (Box 63, Folder 1)
      - Campaign, Mimeos, 1960-70 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - National, Cowles, Mrs. Thomburg, Affiliates Bulletin, 1960-68 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Annual report Distribution, 1970 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Audio-Visual Productions, 1969-71 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - National, the Affiliates' Voice Correspondence, 1968-69 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Audio-Visual, Correspondence, 1969-73 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Clipping Service, 1969-70 (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - Communications Management Project, 1973 (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - Contracts (cross-reference sheets only), 1970-75 (Box 63, Folder 10)
    - Coordinator of Public Affairs, Position Description, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - Environmental Teach-in (Earth Day), 1969-70 (Box 63, Folder 12)
    - Exhibits, 1970-73 (Box 63, Folder 13)
    - Films
      - Vision Associates, A Presentation, circa 1970, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence
        - 1970-74 (Box 63, Folder 15)
        - 1975-77 (Box 63)
      - Bids, 1971 (Box 63, Folder 16)
      - Fairman College Film, 1970-71 (Box 63, Folder 17)
      - Film Directory, 1976, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 18)
      - "Happy Family Planning" (Cartoon), 1969-72 (Box 63, Folder 19)
      - Memos
        - 1970-74 (Box 63, Folder 20)
        - 1975 (Box 63)
      - The National Film Archive, London, England, 1971-72 (Box 63, Folder 21)
      - Permission to Reproduce, 1971 (Box 63, Folder 22)
      - Pregnancy Counseling Training Film, San Francisco/Alameda, 1971 (Box 63, Folder 23)
      - Requests, 1970-74 (Box 63, Folder 24)
      - Sanger Film Project, 1974 (Box 63, Folder 25)